I'm skipping school for
a while starting today.
（圭一(けいいち)）俺さ今日から
しばらく休むことにするよ
これ回覧板ね
Here are the circulating
community notices.
The police are trying
their hardest to find them.
警察も必死に捜してくれてる
I'm sure they'll be found,
so be patient, okay?
きっと見つかるから待ってよう
Missing: Kiichiro Kimiyoshi,
Rika Furude, Satoko Hojo
I'm sure they'll be found,
so be patient, okay?
Missing: Kiichiro Kimiyoshi,
Rika Furude, Satoko Hojo
You're not going
to question me, huh?
（圭一）
レナは俺を問い詰めないんだな
You know, right?
That on that night, I...
レナは知ってるんだろう？
俺があの晩…
（ﾚﾅ）
祭具殿に忍び込んだこと…かな？
You mean sneaking
into the ritual tool shrine?
I guess you know everything.
（圭一）筒抜けなんだなまったく
魅(み)ぃちゃんはすごく怒ってたよ
（圭一）ウッ…
Mi-chan was really mad.
I don't think
anyone punished you.
誰も圭一君を叱らなかったと思う
だから
私が代わりに圭一君を叱るね
So I'll punish you
in place of everyone.
I'm sorry.
俺が…悪かったです
あっ…何だ？これ
What's this?
I'm sharing quality soy sauce
sent by my relatives in Akita.
“秋田の親戚から届いた
本場仕込みのお醤油(しょうゆ)―”
“お分けします
お気軽に園崎(そのざき)までどうぞ”
Feel free to contact Sonozaki.
レナお前知ってたのか？
Rena, you knew?
I'm going to Mion's place.
I'll apologize.
俺魅音(みおん)の所へ行く　謝ってくるよ
もう全部終わりにしてもらう
I want her to end all of this.
- "Cotton Drifting" Chapter -
Episode 04: WISH
When They Cry
Behind where I looked back
(who's there in the front)?
I raised my nails in the dark
(and slashed the night).
Raindrops become droplets of
blood and drip down the throat.
If you don't have
a place to go back to...
...then stop here on my finger.
I'll take you away
along with that finger.
To the unopenable
forest where cicadas cry.
You can't turn back anymore.
I see...
（大石(おおいし)）なるほど
Don't you feel relieved
now that you've said it all?
（大石）
どうです？話したらなんだか
すっきりしたんじゃないですか？
（無線の受信音）
（熊谷(くまがい)）熊谷です大石さんどうぞ
This is Kumagai.
Oishi-san, over.
Yes, hello, this is Oishi.
はいもしもし大石です
（熊谷）先ほど学校に
欠席するとの連絡があったそうです
I heard earlier she notified
the school that she'll be absent.
園崎家前は動きなし
標的はまだ邸内です
No activity in front of the Sonozaki
house. Target is still inside.
Okay, please continue
the surveillance.
（大石）はいはい
引き続き見張りお願いします
了解ッス
Got it.
Um...
あの…
ありゃ…聞こえちゃいました？
Oops, did you hear that?
The chief hasn't given
permission for a probe.
課長から
内偵の許可もらってないんですよ
事情聴取も家宅捜査もとにかく
な～んにも許可が下りないんですわ
We've had no luck
getting permission...
...to question her
or to search the house.
令状がなくっちゃ私たち
な～んも手出しできませんからね
We can't attempt to do
anything without a warrant.
現行犯以外は
Unless she's caught red-handed.
大石さんって…
ひょっとして圭一君をたきつけて
Oishi-san...
Could it be you're
prodding Keiichi-kun...
園崎家に踏み込ませようと
してたんじゃないですか？
...to go inside
the Sonozaki house?
そして圭一君に何かあれば
それを口実に踏み込むつもりだった
And if anything happened...
...you planned to use it
as an excuse to enter.
そうでしょう？
Isn't that right?
Even if as a result,
Keiichi were to get attacked...
その結果
圭一君が襲われるかもしれないのに
いやいやこりゃ…
とんだ所に名探偵がいたもんです
Oh, to think we'd have
a supersleuth in this kind of place.
恥知らず！
これが警察のやり方なの？
You're shameless!
Is this the way police do things?
（ドアの開く音）
レ…レナ！
R-Rena!
Oh, Oishi to Kuma-chan, over.
あ～大石より熊ちゃんへどうぞ
This forest...
（圭一）この森…いや山が
まるまる庭なのか？
No, the mountain is
all part of their garden?
Sonozaki
Mion.
まず謝ることがある
First, I have to apologize.
圭ちゃんが？何を？
You? For what?
あの綿流しの晩
俺は神社の祭具殿に入ったんだ
On Cotton Drifting Festival night,
I went into the ritual tool shrine.
入ってはいけない場所だってのは
知ってた
I knew I wasn't
supposed to enter it.
でもほんのちょっとした
探検のつもりで…
But I treated it like
a little exploration...
悪気はなかったんだ
I didn't mean any harm.
謝る！このとおり！
I apologize! I'm sorry!
It's already been
a few days since then.
あれからもう何日もたってる
今更だとは思うが謝る　悪かった
It may be too late,
but I apologize. I'm sorry.
圭ちゃんが
悪いことをしたと思ったなら―
If you feel you did a bad thing,
then I think that's enough.
それでいいんじゃないの？
魅ぃちゃん
圭一君は真面目に謝ってるんだよ
Mi-chan.
Keiichi-kun is
seriously apologizing.
魅ぃちゃんも真剣に
答えてあげるべきじゃないのかな？
Shouldn't you seriously respond
to him too? Shouldn't you?
かな？
私は真剣だよ
レナには不真面目そうに見えるの？
I am being serious.
Does it look like
I'm not being serious?
見えるよ
It does.
Keiichi-kun, that's enough.
Let's tell her everything.
圭一君もういいよ　全部話そう
It seems like that's
what Mi-chan wants.
魅ぃちゃんも
それを望んでるようだし
魅音おととい梨花(りか)ちゃんと
沙都子(さとこ)を呼んだろう？
Mion, you called Rika and Satoko
over two days ago, didn't you?
夕方過ぎのお夕食の前の時間
梨花ちゃんが来たはずだよ
Rika should've come before
dinnertime in the evening.
She came with a big bottle
for some soy sauce.
お醤油の大瓶を持って
お裾分けしてもらいに
And then you hid her away.
そして魅ぃちゃんは
梨花ちゃんを…隠してしまった
It was actually
supposed to end there.
本当はそれで
終わりのはずだったんだよね？
For you...
魅ぃちゃんにとっては
（魅音）
そりゃどういう意味かな？
What's that supposed to mean?
梨花ちゃんが
魅ぃちゃんの家に行くことを―
You didn't expect Rika...
...would tell Satoko that she
was going to your place, right?
沙都子ちゃんに言い残していたのは
誤算だったんじゃないかな
冷蔵庫の中に沙都子ちゃんの
作った２人分のお夕食が―
The dinner Satoko made for two
was left untouched in the fridge...
まるまる手付かずで残ってたから
...so that tells us what you said to
Satoko when you called her over.
それが魅ぃちゃんが沙都子ちゃんを
呼び出した話の内容まで―
如実に物語っちゃってるの
ハハッ…これは…
This...
アハハハッ！まいった
まいった降参だよ
Oh man. Oh man, I give up!
ハァ～ッ…
ああもう！
Jeez!
村長さんも魅ぃちゃんが？
（圭一）富竹(とみたけ)さんと鷹野(たかの)さんも？
Was the village
headman also your...
Tomitake-san
and Takano-san too?
（魅音）
はじめまして　ご挨拶申し上げます
Pleased to meet you.
Let me introduce myself.
I am the heir to the head
of the Sonozaki family, Mion.
園崎本家当主跡継ぎ
魅音でございます
私にお話しできることでしたら
包み隠さずお話ししたいと存じます
I intend to talk honestly and
openly to the best of my ability.
雛見沢(ひなみざわ)がかつて―
Did you know that Hinamizawa
was called Onigafuchi Village?
鬼ヶ淵(おにがふち)村と呼ばれていたことを
ご存じですか？
The ancestors
from Onigafuchi Village...
鬼ヶ淵村のご先祖さまたちは―
鬼の血を引く
誇り高き仙人たちでした
...were descendents with
demon blood and proud sages.
でも麓の村の人々は―
But the villagers near
the base called us "demons"...
“鬼だ”と私たちを蔑み
石を投げました
...despised us,
and threw rocks at us.
To fight such unjust people,
the people of Hinamizawa...
雛見沢の人々は
そんな理不尽な相手と戦うために
...formed a faction
to stand against them.
徒党を組んで
立ち向かうようになったのです
Kei-chan, when ruffians
attacked you in town...
圭ちゃんも街で不良に襲われたとき
...do you recall being
rescued by many people.
たくさんの人たちに助けられたのを
思い出しませんか？
For Hinamizawa to be
a holy existence again...
（魅音）
雛見沢を再び鬼ヶ淵村のように
あがめられるに足る神聖な存在に
...revered like Onigafuchi Village.
That is the dearest wish of
the village's descendents...
それが
我ら鬼ヶ淵村の末裔(まつえい)の悲願であり
園崎家の
“鬼を継ぐ者”の宿命なのです
...and the fate of the Sonozaki
family, heirs to the demon.
（圭一）“鬼を継ぐ者”？
Heirs to the demon?
園崎家は代々当主の名に―
For each generation
in the Sonozaki family...
“鬼”の１文字を
加える習慣があるのです
...it's customary to add "demon"
to the family head's name.
魅音の“魅”にも“鬼”の字
（ﾚﾅ）あっ…
The "mi" in Mion is
the character for "demon."
It is not just the name.
名前だけではありませんよ
この体にも鬼が刻まれているのです
There is also a "demon"
engraved on my body.
いいよ魅ぃちゃん
見せる必要なんて全然ない
It's okay, Mi-chan.
There's no need at all to show it.
Thank you.
ありがとう
About the serial deaths
these five years...
（魅音）この５年の連続事件ね
私が直接関わったものもあるし
間接的に関わったものもある
I was directly involved in some...
...and indirectly involved in others.
園崎家だけでなくほかの御三家が
関わってるものもあるけど
The other three families did some,
not just the Sonozaki family...
その全ての中心に私がいたと思う
...but I believe I was
in the center of them all.
でも魅ぃちゃんは梨花ちゃんと
沙都子ちゃんを殺したんだよね？
But you killed Rika-chan
and Satoko-chan, right?
I won't make excuses.
（魅音）弁解はしないよ
The demon dwells
in my name and in my body...
私には鬼が宿ってる
名前にも体にも
...and in my heart.
心にも…
But you spared just one
person of your own will.
だけど魅ぃちゃんは
自分の意思で１人だけ救ったんだね
（魅音）さぁて
どうして殺さなかったのかねえ
Well, I wonder why
I didn't kill that person.
鬼の私にゃ見当もつかないわ
As a demon, I have no idea.
魅音のほうに殺したくない都合でも
あったんじゃないの？
Perhaps Mion had reasons
for not wanting to kill?
どういう意味だよ？
（ﾚﾅ）し～っ…
What does that mean?
Oishi is outside, right?
（魅音）
大石は外にいるんでしょう？
あっ…
（ﾚﾅ）うん多分
Probably.
- Is there a way out?
- I don't think so.
逃げ場は？
（ﾚﾅ）ない…と思う
Turn yourself in.
We'll go with you.
自首しよう　私たちも一緒に行くよ
親友を
１人きりになんか絶対にしない
We'd never leave
our best friend alone.
I guess I can't win against Rena.
（魅音）
泣く子とレナには勝てないわ
Before that...
その前に30分でいいから
圭ちゃんと２人きりにしてほしい
...I'd like you to leave me and
Kei-chan alone for 30 minutes.
May I hold your arm?
腕…組んでもいいかな？
I don't mind.
別にかまわないぞ…
It seems Shion also liked you.
（魅音）詩音も
圭ちゃんのことが好きだったみたい
R-Really?
（圭一）そ…そうなんだ？
Shion is still alive.
詩音はまだ生きている
なっ…本当か？
Really?
Come with me.
来て
私の罪の全てを見てほしいから
I want you to see
all of my crimes.
既に起こり
終わってしまった事実だけれども
Though all this has already
happened and ended for a fact...
何を見たって…
（魅音）うん
No matter what I see...
To me, Mion Sonozaki
is the greatest best friend.
俺にとっての園崎魅音は
最高の親友だ　それは変わらない
That won't change
for the rest of my life.
一生
あんたもレナも―
Why do you and Rena become
so cool at times like these?
どうしてこんなときばかり
カッコよくなるんだろうね
When They Cry
（魅音）引き返すなら今だよ
Now's the time to turn back.
I'll keep saying it. Mion Sonozaki
is my greatest best friend.
（圭一）何度だって言う
園崎魅音は俺の最高の親友だ
魅音があんたを好きになったの
分かる気がする
I think I know
why Mion liked you now.
こんな所に農具が…
（扉の閉まる音）
Farm tools in a place like this...
Mion.
魅音…
You looked inside
the ritual tool shrine, right?
祭具殿の中見たよね？
Those torture tools...
あの拷問道具は全て―
鬼ヶ淵村の厳しい戒律を
守るために作られた物だった
...were all made to enforce
Onigafuchi Village's harsh precepts.
Those who broke the precepts
were cruelly killed as a lesson.
戒律を破った者を見せしめに
むごたらしく殺してみせる
They were such tools.
そういう道具だった
大昔の話だろう？
（魅音）園崎家は作ったの
That was long ago, right?
My family created it for the cotton
drifting ritual, even in present day...
現代でも綿流しの儀が行えるように
秘密の場所を
...a secret place.
These are observation seats.
鑑賞席だよ
みんなここで私が殺した
私は綿流しを上手にやってみせた
I killed them all here.
I performed the cotton
drifting well in front of them.
Where's Shion?
詩音は？
（魅音）向こうが牢屋(ろうや)
The prison over there.
Where are
Satoko and Rika-chan?
沙都子と梨花ちゃんは？
虫が湧くとイヤだったから
井戸に捨てちゃったよ
I didn't want maggots to come,
so I threw them in a well.
Sorry.
ごめん
（圭一）ウッ…
詩音！
Shion!
（詩音）圭ちゃん？
Kei-chan?
あっ！詩音！
Shion!
Kei-chan?
圭ちゃん？圭ちゃん
Kei-chan!
圭ちゃん！圭ちゃん…
Kei-chan...
Thank goodness you're okay.
（圭一）良かった
無事だったんだな
No!
（詩音）イヤー！
I can't take this anymore! No!
もうイヤ！イヤー！
If you hate me, kill me!
私が憎いなら私を殺してよ！
- Hurry up and kill me!
- Calm down, Shion!
早く殺して！
落ち着け詩音もう終わったんだ
It's over!
（魅音）
フフッ…そんなに死にたければ
If you really want
to die that much...
この男を殺したあとで
ゆっくりとひき肉にしてやるよ
...after I kill this guy, I'll slowly
make you into mincemeat.
No!
（詩音）イヤー！
（魅音）フフフフッ…
Can you hear, Shion?
It's about to begin!
聞こえるかい？詩音
これから始まるよ
圭ちゃんの悲鳴を
たっぷりと楽しみな
Enjoy Kei-chan's
screams to the fullest!
ようやくお目覚め？
You're finally awake?
Who are you?
お前は誰だ？
はぁ？園崎魅音でしょう
Mion Sonozaki.
You can't possibly be Mion.
お前が魅音であるはずがない
Really? Then who
am I supposed to be?
へえ…じゃ私は誰なわけ？
鬼だ
You're a demon.
フフッ…圭ちゃん
Kei-chan,
I'll tell you only one thing.
ひとつだけ教えてあげるよ
（圭一）あっ…
私の中に鬼が宿ったのは随分前
The demon dwelled
in me for quite a while.
One thing triggered
its awakening.
それがあることをきっかけに
目覚めてしまった
You're the main reason
why everything got screwed up.
あんたが
全てを狂わせてしまった元凶
If you only had given the doll
you got to Mion that time...
あのときあんたがもらった人形を
魅音に渡していたなら
全ては
狂いださなかったかもしれない
...everything may not
have fallen apart.
あんたが魅音を泣かさなかったら
私は起きなくて済んだのにね
If you hadn't made Mion cry,
I wouldn't have woken up.
この拷問はねとってもシンプル
This torture is really simple.
右手と左手15本ずつ
関節にクギを打っていく
I'll hammer fifteen nails into
your right and left hands' joints.
（魅音）あっ…
なんでだろう？躊躇(ちゅうちょ)しちゃうよ
Why is this?
I'm hesitating.
それで魅音の鬼が収まるのなら
気の済むようにやってくれ
If that'll calm Mion's demon,
do it until you're satisfied.
Really?
本気？
（圭一）その代わり２つ約束しろ
But in exchange,
promise me two things.
Please forgive Shion.
詩音は許してやれ
（魅音）この期に及んで
自分よりも詩音の心配？
Even now, you're more worried
about Shion than yourself?
もうひとつは
その体を魅音に返してやってくれ
The other is to please
give that body back to Mion.
それだけだ
That's it.
命請いするとか
そういう考えは思い浮かばないの？
You're not even thinking
about begging for your life?
Then the third one
is not to kill me.
じゃ３つ目は“俺を殺すな”だ
最初に２つって言ったでしょう
だからもうダメ
You said two initially.
So no more.
That's too bad.
そいつは残念
多分私は約束を守らないよ
鬼だから
I probably won't keep
the promises since I'm a demon.
でも今の３つ目の願いだけは
聞いてもいいよ
But I don't mind granting
just your third wish.
To save Shion...
That's impossible now.
“詩音を救うこと”
これはもうムリ
Since the demon will kill Shion,
that can't be stopped.
詩音は鬼が殺してしまうから
もう止められない　諦めて
Give it up.
To give this body back to Mion...
That's also impossible now.
“この体を魅音に返すこと”
それももうムリ
Can you hear that sound?
聞こえる？あの音
（圭一）あっ…
Since you weren't coming back,
Rena probably called Oishi.
（魅音）帰りが遅いから
レナが大石を呼んだってとこかな
ごめんね魅音を汚(けが)して
I'm sorry for desecrating Mion.
No matter what happens,
the Mion within me won't change.
何があっても
俺の中の魅音は変わらない
But forget about it.
でも忘れて　今日以後
私を見かけても近寄らないでね
Even if you see me after today,
don't come near me.
それは私の屍(しかばね)に取りついた…
It'll just be the demon
that possessed my corpse.
鬼なんだから
Hey, two stretchers!
（救急隊員）おい担架２つ！
We've rescued Keiichi Maebara
and Shion Sonozaki.
（警官）
前原(まえばら)圭一園崎詩音の両名を救出
圭一君！圭一君！
Keiichi-kun! Keiichi-kun!
（圭一）
魅音はまだ捕まっていない
Mion hasn't been caught yet.
The bodies of the victims
also haven't been found yet.
ほかの犠牲者たちの死体も
まだ見つかっていない
Kumagai-san!
（鑑識）熊谷さん
（熊谷）うん？
What a horrible crime.
The culprit was a...
（ｷｬｽﾀｰ）すごい事件でしたね
犯人がなんと女子…
I see... You're moving away.
（ﾚﾅ）
そっか引っ越しちゃうんだね…
It's going to be lonely.
I'm the only one left.
寂しくなるね　私１人しか残らない
（圭一）こんな所をうろついてて
大丈夫なのかよ？
Is it okay to be
wandering around here?
I wanted to talk
to you one last time.
最後に話がしたかったから
私ねもうここにはいられない…
I can't stay here anymore.
おい大丈夫か？
Hey, are you okay?
I've tried hard until today...
今日までが…頑張ってきたけど
もうダメ…
...but I can't anymore.
ハハッ…アハハハッ…
（圭一）ハッ…おい
Hey.
ハァハァ…
（圭一）大丈夫かよ？
Are you okay? Don't overdo...
ムリするな…
（刺す音）
ハハッ…アハハハッ！間に合った
I did it in time!
できた！全部できた！
I did it! Did it all!
I killed everyone I wanted to kill!
私が殺したいヤツはこれで全員！
（大石）詩音さんお気の毒に
この高さじゃ即死でしょうね
Poor Shion-san.
It must've been
instant death at this height.
We'll check this out as
a murder and accident.
（熊谷）
事故と事件の両面で捜査します
Right.
It can't be an accident.
（圭一）事故なわけない
Mion hasn't been found yet?
魅音は
まだ見つからないんですか？
（大石）そうそう
それをお伝えしたくて来たんですよ
Oh, right. I came
here to update you on that.
She was actually found.
実は見つかったんです
Ow...
それだけじゃない
井戸も見つかったんです
That's not all.
The well was also found.
前原さんの
おっしゃっていたとおり―
As you said,
we found the bodies...
...of all the missing people
at the bottom of the well.
失踪者全員の遺体を
その底で発見しました
By the way, Maebara-san.
ところで前原さん
あなた本当に
園崎魅音に刺されたんですか？
Did you really get
stabbed by Mion Sonozaki?
（ライターの着火音）
はい
Yes.
Oishi-san,
this is a nonsmoking area.
大石さんここ禁煙ですよ
実は園崎魅音も
井戸の底から見つかったんですよ
Actually, Mion Sonozaki was also
found at the bottom of the well.
しかも我々が突入したあの日に
死んだらしいのです
In fact, it appears that she died
the day we swarmed the place.
T-Then who
attacked me and Shion?
じゃ…じゃ誰が…
誰が 俺と詩音を襲ったんですか？
鷹野三四(みよ)さんの死覚えてますか？
Do you remember
Miyo Takano-san's death?
えっ？はい
確か焼け死んだって聞いたような
Yes, I heard she burned to death.
検視の結果死後24時間経過って
出ちゃったんです
The autopsy results said her body
was found 24 hours after death.
（大石）つまり…
So when you all snuck into the
ritual tool shrine on festival night...
あなた方とお祭りの晩
祭具殿へ忍び込んだときには―
...Takano-san was already dead.
鷹野さんはもう
お亡くなりになってたってことに
Corpses are walking around
too much in this case.
今回の事件
死体が歩き回り過ぎなんですよ
At that time,
I granted you one wish...
（魅音）
あのとき１つかなえてあげたけど
...but not anymore.
やっぱりダ～メ
To get my happiness,
I had done everything...
...but had done nothing
to be blamed and accused of.
The sound of footsteps
became louder every day.
Then I noticed the fact
there was no time.
I was a believer in life,
to be myself always.
And was asking
whether I would be alive.
Give me a reason
why not to adopt in this way.
Or judge me to be guilty
of so many incurable sins.
Tell me why or why not?
Complaining way too much.
Maybe I overlooked
something fatal for me.
Preview
What I'm forgetting
is your warmth.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
忘れているのはあなたのぬくもり
繰り返される
悲しみの足音
The repetition of
the sound of sad footsteps.
The memory fragment
that lures one to the door.
扉へと
いざなう記憶のかけら
When They Cry.
「ひぐらしのなく頃に」
"Curse Killing" Chapter,
Episode 1: OLDER BROTHER
- "Curse Killing" Chapter -
Episode 01: OLDER BROTHER
"Curse Killing" Chapter,
Episode 1: OLDER BROTHER
Can you believe it?
あなたは信じられますか？